Jeff and I have had a lot of discussions
Jeff et habuisse multum disputationibus
on the air about artificial intelligence
in aerem fere artificialis intelligentia,
and opinions thereof but the fact is
sed eius rei sententiaeque
artificial intelligence is no longer a
non est artificialis intelligentia est
thing of science fiction but we tend to
sed tendunt ad rem de scientia ficta
get our information from mainstream
ut a nostris informationes amet
media and so we're hearing about hype
et media hype ita et nos de auditu
and speculation and often fear-mongering
et speculatio saepe et timore-mongering
from people who haven't themselves been
qui non fuerunt ab
contributors to the technology our guest
technology id conferunt ad hospitem nostrum,
this week wants to change that with his
Hoc septimana vult mutare suis
new book architects of intelligence
nova intelligentia libro de architectis
where he's recorded in-depth interviews
quo suus in-profundum colloquiis memoriae
with the very people shaping the future
cum ipsi futura faciebat
of AI he's the New York Times
AI quod est in New York Times
bestselling author of rise of the robots
bestselling author of ortus robots
please help me welcome futurist Martin
placere adiuva me receperint Martin futurist
Ford Martin it's great to have you on
Ford Martin suus 'magnum habere in te
the show thanks for joining us yeah
yeah spectaculum gratias agens pro veniendo
thanks Martin why another book about AI
quid aliud agimus Martin libro de intellegentiae artificialis
well what I really wanted to do with
tam quae vere volo ut faciam cum
this book is get inside the minds of the
hoc est, accipere librum intus in animo est
people that are really building this
qui sunt re vera populi huius aedificationem
technology the people that really on you
technology est vere populus in te
know in the whole world know the most
sciunt ignorantibus plerisque orbis
about artificial intelligence they're
ut sis de artificialis intelligentia,
literally in many cases the people that
ad litteram, quod in multis casibus populo
have you know been responsible for some
tu nosti de reus est
of the breakthroughs that have really
re vera autem quae ex breakthroughs
brought us to this point where
introduxit ad locum in quo loco
everybody's talking about AI because
quia suus 'omnes de intellegentiae artificialis
it's become so disruptive so I think
sic fiet puto suus 'tam turbulentos
that's the best way to kind of cut
quod optime genus incidere
through as you said the speculation and
propter quod dicitur in speculatione
the hype and really find out what's
Et quid suus 'vere invenietis ex hype
really going on and that's sort of my
et quod suus 'vere agatur generis mei
purpose with this book very good and I
ad hoc ipso liber et bona
love the way it reads
amant eam per viam legit,
it is written very much as an interview
simillimus est colloquium
so you know if you're daunted by a big
igitur si tu scis te erant 'a magnus Stygis iuratos
thick book Architects of intelligence
Architectus densissima libri intelligentia,
from Martin Ford is it's written like an
sicut scriptum est quod suus 'a Ford Martin
interview and you're able to kind of get
conveniendi et genus impetro vestri 'potest
into the minds of those who are involved
versantur in mentibus
in the development of AI Martin how will
ad quam progressus Martin AI erit
AI evolved and what major innovations
Et quod major A. evolved innovations
are on the horizon well I mean that's a
quod est super horizon bene sit a me
good question no one really knows the
nemo vere novit qui bonum quaestio
answer to that and that's one of the
Et respondendum est, quod unus ut '
main takeaways from the book is that I
quae est principalis takeaways ex libro
talked to 23 of the people in the world
XXIII loquebatur ad populi in mundo
that know the most about this and yet
maxime tamen hoc scitote quia
they really don't agree on a lot of this
quod vere non conveniunt in hunc multum
stuff you know to have different
alium habere vos scitis supellectilem
opinions different ideas so one of the
tam diversas opiniones de
main takeaways is that it's gonna be
suus 'agnus dei esse, quod est pelagus takeaways
unpredictable I mean everyone agrees
temeraria caeco I intelliguntur omnes consentiunt,
that this can be very disruptive and
Et hoc potest esse turbulentos
it's gonna be a game changer for the
suus 'agnus dei esse ad ludum mutante
economy for society but we don't really
societatem habemus ad oeconomiam, sed non realiter
know exactly what innovations are gonna
scis exacte quid sumus agnus dei innovations
occur first we don't know for example
primo occurrunt, exempli gratia non scitis
what industries are gonna be transformed
Quid agnus dei industrias eius transfigurentur
first we don't know exactly what the
quod prorsus nesciunt Primus enim
breakthroughs are going to be having
cum iri breakthroughs
said that the primary technology that's
dicitur quod in prima technology ut '
really driving things right now is
vere driving quæ nunc est,
what's called deep learning or deep
aut quid dicatur profundum doctrinae
neural networks which is basically
neural retiacula quae radicaliter
building software in a way that kind of
software ut aedificaretur in genere
roughly emulates the way your brain
roughly aemulatur cerebrum per viam vestram
works you know in terms of the way the
Scio opera secundum modum
neurons are connected and that's the
idque sibi connexa neurons
technology there's really just been
technology ibi suus 'vere iustus est
transformative over maybe the last six
transformative per sex ultima maybe
seven years we've seen incredible
vidi septem annis nobis fidem
breakthroughs we've got systems that of
Comperto quod breakthroughs systems
course are used in self-driving cars now
cursum qui adhiberi cars agitantem modo per se,
toward even really close to to really
in vere et realiter ad
working we've got systems used in
Comperto opus in systems
medicine that can look at a medical
qui spectant ad Medicinae medicinae
image and actually be better than a
et quidem melius quam imaginem
human doctor in some cases that
medicum, ut hominem in quibusdam casibus,
determining is there cancer in that
determinandum est cancer in eo
image
imagini
we've got systems that are translating
Comperto autem translating systems
languages
Linguae
even in real time so it's just stuff
ita etiam tempus est in ipsa suus 'iustus supellectilem
that really just a few years ago with
quod est vere iustus paucis abhinc annis,
science fiction is now happening so we
est modo scientia ficta sic fieri
can expect that over the next year's and
quod in posterum sperare possit anni
decades that technology is going to get
quod technology est iens impetro decennium
a lot better it's gonna evolve become
suus 'agnus dei multus melior facti evolve
much more powerful and that's gonna
fortior est et agnus
continue to drive the disruption and
permanere autem agitare atque conversiones
then further out there are some real
tunc amplius de ipsa aliquid sunt
breakthroughs on the road toward what we
quae respiciebat viam breakthroughs
would call true human level intelligence
mens vero humana vocaret
which is really kind of the holy grail
quae est revera quaedam sanctusque Calix
of this whole field you know building a
scitis agrum aedificare totius
machine that can think at the level of a
Apparatus potest cogitare ex aequo
human being but that's kind of a long
homini tamen ut 'genus longo
path and there are a lot of
et illic es multus of semita
breakthroughs that need to occur before
breakthroughs, quae oportet fieri prius
we get there right and a lot of my
illuc enim recta et multum mihi
discussions in this book are about what
in hoc libro de illis quae sunt disputationibus
exactly are those breakthroughs when
quod sint qui prorsus breakthroughs
might they occur what does that path
quid evenire possent iter
look like and how long will it take us
tamquam nos et quam diu eam accipere
to to get the human level AI that's one
ad eam pertingit ad unum ut 'A.
of the most fascinating questions you
et quaestiones in magna fascinatione
know mm-hmm it's really central to this
hmm mm, centralis hoc scimus suus 'realiter
field Martin we hear a lot of terms AI
Martin agrum non audies verba multum intellegentiae artificialis
and now deep learning what what's the
imo quid nunc cognita
actual relationship between deep
ipsa alta necessitudine
learning and AI well AI is the broadest
AI AI latissimo atque eruditionem
term artificial intelligence really
artificialis intelligentia terminus realiter
means essentially building technology
est per se technology aedificationem
building machines or algorithms that in
algorithms ut in machinis aut aedificationem
some sense think or take on cognitive
aut aliquo sensu, ut putes in cognitiva
capability and can solve problems and
facultatem solvere posse quaestiones
learn in the same way that that people
apud eundem, discere ut, quod
can one facet of that one one area of
unus unam partem istius possunt
that is machine learning which is
Apparatus eruditionis quae est
specifically building algorithms that
scilicet quod aedificationem algorithms
can look at data and can learn and right
notitia possit intueri et cognoscere possint, et rectum
now those terms are used kind of
qui autem verba sunt quidam
interchangeably but what we're seeing
vicissim autem cum illis quae erant '
right now is really machine learning
Apparatus eruditionis est nunc
it's algorithms that look at sometimes
algorithms ut suus 'nunc intueri
massive amounts of data and can learn to
ingens amounts of notitia et non discent
do amazing things from that you know
ut mirabile faceret a rebus scitis
base you know for example looking at a
Vos scitis a basi ad exemplum respiciens
medical imaging determining is there
medicinae imagine determinandum est
cancer there or not and that is really
aut non est et hoc est vere cancer
the disruptive technology but there you
turbulentos technology, sed sunt ibi
know in the future it will become even
scire etiam in futuro fiet ei
broader and will incorporate things like
quae maior et latior fiat tibi sicut incorporate
genuine reasoning and so forth but right
cetera vero rectum rationis
now it's primarily a focus on machine
Nunc suus 'praesertim focus in a apparatus
learning yeah that makes me think like
memini me sentire sicut et scientia
is are we gonna see machine learning and
Apparatus eruditionis sumus videre est agnus
deep learning continue to dominate or
nec diutius dominari doctrinae
are we gonna have other approaches that
qui sumus agnus dei habere alias approaches
are coming to the forefront right so
dextera igitur ecce venient in forefront
before the current boom in deep learning
et current ante cognita BUTIO in altum
if you go back you know more than 10
Si tu scis plus quam X ire
years 15 years there were other areas of
XV anni fuerunt anni alii ex areas
AI that were much more prominent that we
A. quod prominentibus sunt multo magis nos, qui
really focused on and this involved for
focused in quod involved pro hac re
example what was called symbolic
exempli gratia est quae vocatur symbolic
reasoning the ability of computers to
et facultatem ad ratiocinari ex computers
make decisions and to to reason in
facere sententias noscere, iisdemque in ratione:
human-like ways this is where the main
sicut est in homine via pelagus
thrust was although people didn't have a
cum autem non haberet populum conpellet
huge amount of success with that there
ingens ibi prospere
was also expert systems which are the
sive systematorum expertorum, quae sunt etiam
kind of systems for example that do step
exempli gratia quaedam, quae faceret gradus systems
by step thinking and analysis that's the
et analysis gradus quod per cogitandi est
kind of system you basically find in a
quaedam ratio plerumque inveniam in vobis
jet airplane which can fly itself right
jet aeroplanus volare non potest, qui ius ipsum
there was once a time when all of this
quo simul omnia facta
stuff that we now considered to be kind
quod genus effercio nunc esse
of routine was was considered to be
considerandum est autem quod cum exercitatione
artificial intelligence the current boom
artificialis intelligentia hodiernam BUTIO
is in machine learning and teaching
Apparatus eruditionis in doctrina
algorithms that can learn but many
et multi hoc scire possumus algorithms
people think that in the future we'll
Populus cogitare quod tibi placet nobis in futuro
need to bring back some of those earlier
necesse est ut quidam ante eorum
ideas into the picture in order to build
ideas in ut aedificare imaginem
more more generalized powerful
more generativus virtutis
intelligence that's one of the the main
id unum principale intellectum
ideas in a book there's one camp of
illic 'unus de castris liber in ideas
people one group of people that believe
qui credis quia unus est populus coetus
strongly that deep learning is not gonna
vehementer quia non est alta doctrina sit amet
be enough to take us forward to the next
sequenti satis ad nos
level that we're gonna have to bring
quia non campester in ut amet adducere
back some of these more to
haec partim jam
some ideas right but then there are a
sed tunc ideas de iure illic es
bunch of people that I talk to that are
fasciculum populus, qui me loqui
really deep learning enthusiasts they
Et vere studiosi doctrinae
really believe in this technology and
vere in hoc technology, et
that includes people like for example
ut adsint asseclae sicut exempli gratia
Geoffrey Hinton who is very famous
Et Galfridus qui Henton 'ipsum clarissimi
within the AI community for having been
de eo quod A. in civitatem
probably single guy that's most
probabiliter maxime unum guy ut '
responsible for bringing forth his deep
author ejus ad pariendum abyssi
learning revolution he really invented a
cognita re inventam rerum
lot of the technology there and they
sit amet velit ut
believe that deep learning will get
Credo quod erit omni doctrinae genere
better there will be you know and become
melius est esse scis, et facti sunt
more general it will have new
novus enim non erit communioribus
capabilities there will be breakthroughs
capabilities erunt breakthroughs
that will occur within the context of
quod est fieri in context
deep learning or neural networks and
et retiacula et doctrinae neural
that will take us forward so it's really
qui ante nos ita ut suus 'realiter
interesting to talk to these different
hi amet loqui
people about their views of the
de views de populo suo
technology and how it might progress but
Quomodo autem posset progressum technicae
again one of the main takeaways is that
Rursum ille principalis Takeaways
they really don't agree there's
qui illic 'vere non conveniunt
something of a debate between these two
quod inter disputandum de illis duobus
camps mm-hm
mm m castra
and that's one of the I think most
Puto et ex pluribus unum
interesting aspects of it cool and it's
et sic frigus suus 'interesting facies
very much stepping stones I think and
Erg admodum sentio lapidibus
we're at that point where it's leaps and
in qua punctum illud saltibus, elevatur et in ipso sumus
bounds Jeff I'm thinking about deep
Jeff ego cogito terminis abyssi
learning and as you're mentioning Martin
et quod doctrina tibi mentio Martin
how can this technology is able to think
Quo uero huius technology possit cogitare
along the the same kind of way of a
per eandem viam
human in a way so I mean I have to ask
ita ut in homine sit habeo, quaerere
the question that all of us Trekkies are
quaestione sunt omnes ex nobis Astralis
thinking I'm sure at this moment I mean
Certe ego nunc cogitas
what does it look like as far as the
quid simile quantum
path toward human level artificial
humana arte ad id
general intelligence like how far off
Generalis mentem huiusmodi quorsum
are we really from lieutenant data being
qua de re data sunt legati
able to operate our business right right
res juris nostri iure poterit agunt
I mean that's that's the biggest
Tralatione dico, suus 'maximus ut'
question in artificial intelligence and
artificialis intelligentia, et in quaestionem
and and it goes back right to the
et vadit et ius
beginning when Alan Turing in 1950 wrote
Alan Turing in MCML beginning, cum scripsit
a famous paper he asked can a machine
celebre in charta potest a apparatus interrogavit
think and that's where he invented the
quod est cogitare et ex quo genus excogitavit:
Turing test right which many people have
Ius habent, quam multos populos examen Turing
heard of is kind of the test for true
audiens verus modus expertus
intelligence if a machine can carry out
intelligentia machina ferre
a conversation like like a person and we
colloquium ut homo sicut et nos
consider it to be intelligent that's one
quod unus considerat intelligentes
one test and that goes all the way back
quae omnia expertus est via
to right to the beginning and yet we
ad ius ad initium et nos
still don't really know the answer to
adhuc non est responsum cognoscere vere
the question of how how far off it is
quaesitum est quomodo quorsum
and it's it's a big part of the book I
et factum est ut suus 'a magnus partem libri
talked to everyone about that but the
et loquebatur de illo omnibus autem
opinions really vary I talked to Ray
Ray loquebatur ad rem mea sententia discrepo
Kurzweil who's a very
Raimundum Kurzweil, qui suus 'a valde
famous futurist that many people have
Quod multi homines nobilis futurist
heard of he's the guy that is most
Quod ille audiens sit amet
associated with the idea of the
consociata cum idea Dei
singularity
singularitatem
he thinks it's only ten years off 2029
cogitat suus 'tantum decem annis off MMXXIX
Wow he thinks okay we will have human
Wow homo cogitat bene nos habemus
level artificial intelligence and that's
et hoc ordine Intellegentia
a very very aggressive prediction I
ut praedictum est ipsum agere
personally think that's way too
alio modo videtur quod
yeah like is that an aggressive
yeah, quae qualis sit, pugnax
prediction to try to push the industry
consultum ad experiri ad ventilabis industria
or is this a realistic approximation
et hoc est componendus est approximatio
that's his view I mean Google working on
suum visum, qui est opus in Google EGO vilis
these technologies right he's now before
Nunc autem ad ius vitae
he was a guy that kind of wrote books
ipse fuit guy qui scripsit libros genus
and talked about this a lot and an
Et de hoc multum et loquebatur
inventor but now he actually for the
nunc ultro ad inventor
last few years has worked at Google and
novissimo paucos annos ad quem Google et laboraverunt
he's actually working on this so and in
ipse suus 'vere opus in hac est, et in
the interview I did with him it's clear
colloquium cum suus fecit
- he knows what he's talking about in
- sciat hes 'de illis quae sunt in
terms of the details of you know the
Details of verbis de vobis scire
technologies work and also you have to
technologiae et vos have ut elaborare
give that some some credence right but
nisi aliquam de jure fides adhibenda, ut darem
then other people I talked to and one
quarum, vt dixi tibi unum et loquebatur ei
example would be Rodney Brooks who is
exempli gratia esset, Rodney qui Brooks
who is the founder of iRobot Corporation
qui est conditor iRobot Corporation
he's one of the most famous robotics
unum ex clarissimis robotics
experts in the world he thinks it could
experts in mundo cogitat, non poterat
be a hundred and eighty years in the
centum octoginta annorum, et erunt in
future so that's a pretty good range
satis futurum ut a range
right oh wow is it ten years in the
O wow rectum est in annis decem
future or a hundred and eighty years in
futurum, aut centum et octoginta annis
the future
in posterum
I mean 180 years you're really getting
CLXXX annis, erant 'vere questus vestri ut sit
into the the Star Trek era right I think
Iter ad tempus recte videtur stella
when Star Trek was actually set right a
Cum iam posuit ius de Star Trek
couple hundred years in the future so I
centum annorum copulabis, ita ut in futuro
mean that's the range of opinion I I did
non est id rhoncus IV sententiarum
I asked everyone about this I actually
De quo etiam hoc petivit ut omnis,
took an average any err moment not to be
nunc vero non erret ultra medium
about 80 years so okay just at the end
annos circiter LXXX, ita bene sicut ad finem
of this century so I think most of us
plerique saeculi puto
would be quite lucky to still be alive
felix ad satis esset adhuc viveret
if it's really 80 years from now um so
Si suus 'vere LXXX annis posthac tam um
that's what we're talking about it's
Hoc illud est quod super illud erant loquentes
very unpredictable 80 years is about the
quae praevideri non possunt esse circa LXXX annos
average but there certainly are a number
sed mediocris certe est numerus
of people that are much more aggressive
populum autem, qui plenior aliquanto
not just Ray but others think it might
Alii vero non poterat Cicero
be 20 to 50 years somewhere in that
XX ad L annos in aliqua parte esse, quia
timeframe okay but others think it's
Puto autem quod suus 'okay aliis timeframe
hundred years away so that really gives
Dat quadringentos annos sic
you a good sense of just how hard this
tu modo quam sensus bonam difficile est
problem is and how little we know about
et quam parum sciunt de hoc quaestio est,
it how little we know about what it is
sic ut parum scimus de eo quid est,
really gonna take to get to the point
'agnus dei adepto ut accipe illud vere est
where we can build human level
in quo possumus aedificare humana campester
intelligence and
et intelligentia,
how fast those breakthroughs can occur
breakthroughs potest quam istae
so I would expect very oh thanks
Utinam sic confiterentur ipsi debebat
question yeah and I would expect that
Interrogabo et ego memini arbitror
that is the key word its breakthrough
quae clavis est sermo ejus breakthrough
because at one point that breakthrough
quia in una parte quam breakthrough
is gonna happen that's just all of a
omnia fieri ex iusta sit amet
sudden gonna accelerate things you can
potes enim subito accelerari amet
read all about the discussion that we're
legit omnia circa esse disputationem sumus
having basically learn about these
habent plerumque discere de illa
discussions that Martin has had with
Martin habuit cum discussiones illius
these professionals in the AI industry
haec doctorum industria ad AI,
by reading architects of intelligence
legens ex intelligentia architecti
Jeff do you mind throwing to a
Jeff iacerent tibi ad sapiunt
commercial break we've just got to take
commercial confractus nos Ive 'iustus got ut accipe
a really quick quick break here yeah
hic est vere velox velox confractus yeah
yeah so when we come back we're gonna be
yeah reversus est cum erant 'agnus dei esse
speaking with Martin Ford about the
Martin loqui ad Ford de
dangers associated with AI so you're
pericula consociata cum AI ut vos es
gonna want to stick around whether you
utrum vos volo inhaero circum amet
shop on thinkgeek gearbest B&amp;H photo
TABERNA ThinkGeek gearbest in B &amp; C photo
video eBay or Amazon or even if you want
Amazon et eBay, aut si vos volo video
a free trial of audible you'll find the
libera iudicium de sensibili et youll 'reperio
best deals and support the shows we
optime enim ostendit quod agit et sustinet,
produce by simply visiting the shopping
visitare solum ad producendum per shopping
sites you already frequent by using the
ad frequentes iam sitibus quas utendo
links on our website visit category-five
Nexus in nostro visit quinque-genus
TV slash partners for the full and
TV VULNUS sociis ad plenum
ever-growing list and help us create
et adiuva creare album nobis cotidie
more free content like this show thank
magis liberum contentus sic ostende laudis
you for shopping with our partners and
et ad mercatum it cum sociis ac nostrum
thank you for watching and we're back we
Wisi enim ad insidias sanctificationi, et sumus et nos back
are talking to Martin Ford about his
Martin locuti sunt ad Ford eius per circuitum
he's best-selling author and we're
et auctor suus 'optimus-venditionis et sumus
talking to him about his book on
de eo loquitur, ut ejus librum
artificial intelligence called
qui dicitur artificialis intelligentia,
architects of intelligence now prior to
iam prior ad fabrorum vel ab intelligentia,
the break we had a couple of great
et confractus habebat duobus magnis
questions just kind of going through
Quaestiones quaedam iusta perambulabat
what is artificial intelligence deep
quod est artificialis intelligentia abyssi
learning how are they connected stuff
quae vasa sunt discat
like that but I want to get to the other
ut quod volo nisi ut ad alterum
side of it because we've had
Quia habuisti partem
conversations on the show and as much as
et ostendunt quam quod ex colloquiis
I love the advancement in tech my very
Te amo magis ad profectum meum in ipso tech
personally I am very worried about the
ego sum valde anxius de personaliter
the security risks that come with this
hic metus, quod venient in securitatem
as part of the conversation usually goes
partem sermonis solet
Jeff we got to stay away from conspiracy
Jeff conspiratio a nobis obtinuit manere
theories we got to be careful of that
Ad hypotheses nos got tuo custodi claustra oris illius
because a lot of the mass media is
quoniam multus est ad instrumenta communicationis
driving toward fear-mongering in a lot
multus contra in metus urget Torpedinis
of ways yeah so so I guess the question
EGO coniecto yeah ita est quaestio de via
I want to know and and in coming up to
Vis scire, et venit usque ad me, et
this interview I think it's the number
Puto hoc spatium numerum
one question I've wanted to ask is what
Ego autem volui interrogare quaerere quid sit
are the risks associated with AI and
sunt metus consociata cum AI,
particularly in the areas of security
in locis praecipue de securitate
privacy bias and potential weaponization
secretum pondus atque potentiale weaponization
sounds like a great question for Martin
magna enim quaestio sonat sicut Martin
our guest Martin Ford right so this is
Martin iure ita est Ford nobis hospitis,
this is a very important question and
Haec quaestio magni momenti est et ipsum
there definitely are some legitimate
Ibi definite sunt nonnulla re- ete affulgeat
concerns there and this is you know was
et hoc est curam scitis eius
again a really important topic in the
et rursus re ad rem
book so there's lots of material there
ut illic 'lots of libri materia est
on this I will just in the beginning I
Hoc autem non solum in initio apud te
want to just make the point that there
iustus volo ut faceret illud punctum est
are really two categories of these risks
Sunt duo genera harum re metus
or dangers and the first one is is what
aut quid periculorum Primum
you just mentioned the things that we're
tu modo locutus es, ut quae
gonna face for sure the things that we
facies 'agnus dei pro certo, quod res est
are already beginning to face an
et iam ad faciem
artificial intelligence so these are
Intellegentia Hæ
very very legitimate fairly immediate
proximo legitimo iure ipsum
concerns that we really need to worried
curam sollicitus, nos vere postulo
about and then there's a second category
et illic 'fere alter genus
of dangers that we might call science
ut vocant scientia periculorum
fiction still at this point very more
tamen magis ad hoc puncto valde ficta
speculative futuristic things that many
Pellentesque a speculativo, qui multi sunt
people consider to be you know
considerans populum ut sciam te,
potentially existential but that's a
sed esse in potentia et ut '
separate category so what I'll let me
Quid ego certe singulos categoria
focus first on on the immediate things
in prima focus in rebus proximum
the things that we really legitimately
quae autem vere legitime
have to worry about it's certainly one
illud certe nemo habet ut fatigo circa
of those is security the reality is that
eorum securitati in re sit, quod
when we have an autonomous system
cum enim ratio iuris,
something that is controlled completely
quod omnino aliquid regitur
by artificial intelligence and there are
artificiali intellegentia atque
no people in the loop then by it's
et ab hominibus neque per loop est
natural to assume that that system is
naturalis enim ratio est ponere
going to be more susceptible to you
tibi fore aptius
hacking or to cyberattack someone else
aut aliquis habitant cyberattack
could contain control of that system or
seu quod ratio non habet imperium
or cause it to stop working just to give
vel ea de causa ut iustus opus ad prohibere
one example imagine that we had
exempli gratia unam imaginari quam habuimus
autonomous trucks driving around
aurigabat circa trucks sui iuris,
delivering all our food to stores to
liberandis omnibus copiis cibum
grocery stores and someone hacked into
grocery thesáuris et in aliquis caedere
that and brought all those trucks to a
et adduxit eos in aliquet
stop I mean that's a pretty big problem
Magna quaestio est satis sit id prohibere me
right and you can imagine many many
vos can imaginari plures ius et plures
things like that so the whole issue of
Itaque huiusmodi eventum totius
security with these systems is is a huge
cum his qui est pignus ingens systems
issue and there's lots of effort being
illic 'lots of conatus esse et normam
put into that and it's gonna be a huge
et posuit in illa suus 'agnus dei esse a ingens
challenge and maybe the single most
et maybe maxime provocatione ad unum
important challenge with with regard to
magni momenti est, cum de provocatione
artificial intelligence and automation
artificialis intelligentia et Automation
more generally is the security issue
plus est fere securitatem exitus
you know the fact that we have to make
scis hoc quod habemus ut
sure that these systems you know are
hi sunt qui certo scitis systems
safe from intrusion whether it's from
ab irruptione tutum utrum suus 'a
criminals or other countries or whatever
sive peccantes vel aliis
and Martin if I may ask along that vein
Martin petit et, si potest esse una vein
whose responsibility is that are there
cuius praeterea quia sunt ibi
regulations to to demand companies that
societates quae condicio postulare, ut iustificationes eius
are manufacturing artificial
qui faciens artificialis
intelligence to to use a security by
intelligentia est sit ut per securitatem
design principle yeah I think there's
yeah consilio puto illic 'principle
gonna be a need to be kind of
agnus dei esse opus esse genus
interaction between government and
regimen et actionem mutuam
between industry there I certainly there
illic certe inter industria ibi
there's a place for regulation I don't
illic 'a locus ut ego non statuere,
think the government can do it all by
omnia possum facere a cogitare imperium
itself I mean the reality is that with
in ipso sit veritas et qui cum
many of these issues we you know there's
multi de his rebus dicimus, quia non est ibi
a place for regulation it's also true
nam verum etiam disciplina locus suus
that the government isn't isn't by
quod imperium non est a
itself competent like the people that
sicut se competens est populus
work in the government don't have the
in operis regimen non habent
knowledge to do this so you want basic
Vis scire hoc ita praecipua
realities that people that work for the
quae res, quod operatur per
government make a lot less money than
Imperium minus pecunia, quam multa facere
people in the private sector so the very
ita etiam in privatis
best people don't always work in the
Populus non semper optimum in operatur
government right so in terms of
tam in iure imperii termini
technical expertise it's not always
Non semper ea technica peritiam
there so it's gonna require cooperation
suus 'agnus dei esse et cooperante requirere
between the companies that are doing
inter societates quae agis
this and the government and hopefully
quod hopefully hoc imperium
there can be some reasonable standards
non possunt esse signa aliquid rationabile
there you know and and the companies
et sciunt ibi, et societates
will understand it there probably does
et quod intelligere non est verisimile
need to be regulation to ensure that
necesse est ut lex
that these systems are safe and they
quod haec sint systems et tutum
will work together with the government
et cum imperio cooperantur
to make that happen in an appropriate
ut fiat apta
way okay now I mean along that vein of
iam bene venae intelliguntur per viam illam
thinking you also have the impact of AI
AI ratus ictum habes
as it relates to industries and so with
ita ut respicit amet
that challenge you write about in rise
quod scribis in provocationem ortum
of robots is the potential impact on the
robots est potentiale labefactum in
job market and the economy do you think
Job frugalitas et in foro putatis quia inaniter
that all of this could cause a new kind
hanc novam speciem totam
of industrial revolution and completely
omnino ex odio
transform the job market yeah I mean
transform officium medium forum yeah me
that's my view and as you say that was
ut mihi visum, et hoc erat ut dicis
the topic of my book rise of the robots
in libro topic meam ortus in robots
and I also I talked a lot about that
et multum etiam et loquebatur de illo
with everyone in architects of
cum quisque in architecti
intelligence as well there is something
tum quod sit intelligentia,
of a debate about that you will find for
de disputandum de illo quia vestrum adprehendet vos
sure economists that will tell you that
fideles amen dico vobis quia qui economists
this is all overblown there's nothing to
hoc nihil est omnis quievit
worry about and largely the reason
et late solliciti de causa
they'll tell you there's nothing to
amen dico vobis quod youll 'nihil est
worry about is the in the past this
solliciti de est quod de praeteritis
issue is come up many times people
causa est multis temporibus
worried about technological unemployment
sollicitus otium technological
for a long time
diu
it hasn't really happened yet right so I
non tamen ea re factum est ut ius
personally believe that this time is
personaliter credere quod hoc est,
different because now we've got
Comperto ergo quod aliud
artificial intelligence we've got
Comperto artificialis intelligentia,
machines that are in a limited sense
quae in stricto sensu sit machinis
beginning to think and that means that
coepit cogitare quod id
they are competing you might say with
dicere enim possis contendere
our core competence right the thing that
Caput nostrum ius rei competit
really makes us unique as human beings
unique ut realiter planto nos homines
is our ability to think to learn to
facultatem ad discere cogitare noster
adapt to innovate and machines are
innovate et aptet ut non machinis
beginning to compete directly with this
Certatim beginning protinus huic
capability and that's gonna have a
et quod suus 'agnus dei facultatem habere
different impact in the future that's my
aliud quod in futuro impulsum mihi
view most of the people where everyone
considerabit ubi summa populi omnes
that I talk to really and architects of
quod re vera loqui de architectis
intelligence believes that there is
credit quod intelligentia sit
going to be a disruptive impact not
turbulentos impetus non futurum
everyone agrees there will be outright
ab omnibus conceditur omnino erunt
unemployment but I mean I think most
sed intelliguntur otium maxime puto
people in the technology community
In technology populus civitatis
believe in the potential word is big
Credo in Verbo magna est potentiale
disruption what we see so far of course
quatenus scilicet perturbatio videmus
is not unemployment we've got a very low
Comperto sapien non nimis
unemployment rate in the United States
otium rate in Civitatibus Foederatis Americae
but we do see for example stagnant wages
sed quod videt, mercedem stagna exempli gratia
right among most right oh the workforce
o ius in dextera eorum tria summa
you know they literally haven't gotten a
ipsi scitis quoniam ad verbum non est consecutus
raise really in decades not in not after
Non post decennium in re non suscipies
and adjusting for inflation so I think
ac componi eas in incremento pretiorum ut puto
technology is already having a big
habens technology iam magnum
impact in terms of pushing down wages
mercedem secundum ictum deprimentes
for average people and making things
et ad faciendum uulgi
much more unequal so - all the gains
tam multa proelium par - omnes: verbosa gaudet
from advancing technology are now going
nunc progredi technica
to the people at the top right
in vertice dextra usque ad populum
executives and investors and people like
et quod populus amo executives elit
that are doing well but average people
sed quae bene uulgi
are not so I think this is already
non puto hoc ita est, iam
having a big impact and I personally
et tamen cum magno impetu
believe that over the next 10 20 years
credo in proximo X annis XX
we're gonna see an even bigger impact
erant 'videre' agnus dei esse maior vel impulsum
and there is a real potential for for
et verum est quia est potentiale
unemployment and that's an issue that is
et id quod est per otium proventus
you know potentially huge for society
et vos societatem ingens potentia;
for the fabric of society for stability
ad societatem afficiant, quaque stabilitate
of society for political stability and
nam in societatem rei publicae constantiam,
so forth not just in the US but in
et fructum non solum in US, sed
countries across the world right and it
regionibus trans mundi, et ius
also has big economic implications
economic magnus effectus habet
because in order to have a thriving
quia ad hoc sime
economy people have to have money to
pecunias habere et oeconomia
spend right you you know you need people
Vos scitis iustum populus habe tibi necessaria
to come by what's being produced
quid ipsae venire
businesses need customers and if people
Si populus elit elit et opus
don't have jobs or if their incomes are
Jobs non sunt vel redditibus
very low if things are so unequal that a
Quod si ita est nimis inaequalia
few people are really capturing all the
qui pauci sunt, omnes rem caperent
income then you can't really have a
tunc vos can non realiter habent reditus
a vibrant economy and I think that's
et Vividiorque oeconomiam puto ut '
gonna be a real challenging for us so
agnus dei esse verum, sic nos provocans est
you got is my view although again there
etsi mihi non accepisti factum est
is a big debate over it okay
a magnus bene sit disputandum in illa
now I mean with that thought I mean
hoc autem dico quod dixi
you've talked about how big business is
Magna res est, quam locutus est de te
gonna be gaining from that and I know I
et scies quia ego sum reportando a amet
read an article earlier this week about
quod ante hoc legitur articulus de septimana
a I think it was a restaurant in Japan
puto enim fuit popina in Japan
or China that had laid off all of its
quae posita vel elit singula
staff and got robots in and then fired
et surrexit et accensus est in virgam robots
them all essentially because they
quia per eos
weren't working out so with that kind of
ita non opus genus
back and forth hustle of trying to get a
qui egrediebatur et revertebatur Turbam rerum hominumque trying impetro in
sense of how to use AI who really is
Quam ad rem, qui est sensus intellegentiae artificialis
going to be the big benefactor and who
et magnum futurum beneficium
are going to be the big losers is it
erit enim magnus ire Serpentis
kind of the you know big man versus
ad versus tibi magnum quoddam
little man or is it gonna create a whole
illud totum nesciet aut agnus homunculum
new realm of winners and losers so to
realm of novus ut uictorum et victos
speak well it's going to I mean
suus 'iens ut bene sit tibi loqueris
technology is gonna have a gradual
agnus dei habere sit technology certamen
impact right it's not going to be a
ictum, non iudicium futurum
restaurant for you know robots overnight
scitis enim caupona pernoctare robots
or something it's going to be a
aut quid suus 'iens futurus est
restaurant gradually using more robots
popina plures successive per robots
and as a result of that not meeting
Et propter hoc, non quasi occurrens
quite as many people and maybe letting
quod satis multis, et ad internecionem maybe
some people go and maybe not hiring so
aliqui non datur inpiis, et vado ut hiring
many people in the future right and
multi dextris et in futuro
you're gonna see that in restaurant
tu amet, videatur in caupona
you're gonna see that in Amazon
es agnus dei videatur in Amazon
warehouses and you're gonna see it
et videbit eum horreis amet
especially with white-collar jobs across
praesertim cum album-torquem per jobs
the board so this is one really
et haec est vere tabula
important thing to understand is that
magni momenti est intelligere, quod
this is not just blue-collar workers and
hoc non est iustum, et hyacintho-torquem operantur
it's certainly not just physical robots
suus 'non iustus physica robots certe
and they're actually manipulating the
et illi erant 'actu deformetur
world right it's a lot of this is just
mundus est rectum est iustus multum
about software and it's gonna be a big
et de suus 'agnus dei esse a magnus software
impact on knowledge workers the people
impulsum operarios in notitiam populi
that sit in front of a computer and do
qui in conspectu Dei sedent a computer et facit
relatively routine things you know
exercitatione secundum quid nosti omnia
cranking out the same report again and
atque idem ex cranking
again or doing the same kind of
seu etiam eadem
quantitative analysis or manipulating
quantitatis analysis vel abusionibus
data in some way a lot of it is gonna be
data multum aliqualiter sit amet
susceptible to automation and that's not
et hoc obnoxios esse non Automation
you know low-skilled people right that's
quod velox humili scire iustitiam
people that have college degrees
habere collegium gradus, ut populus
so there's a big impact coming there now
et veniens ibi nunc illic 'a magnus impulsum
in general the losers are going to be
Perdiderunt futurum omnino
people that do routine repetitive
populus qui faciunt repetita exercitatione
predictable things and again right that
et rursus illa praedictio
doesn't necessarily mean unskilled
non imperitus necessario
people or people that don't have
et qui non est populus
education it's about the nature of the
educationem est de natura
work there might be the McDonald's
Non est opus esset mcdonald
worker flipping hamburgers or it might
vel operante ut hamburgers flipping
be the college graduate
esse collegium graduate
who just does the same report every week
non fama solum, qui simul omni septimana
right those people can both be impacted
et ea iure posse quin impacted
the people that are going to be the
populus autem iens futurus est
winners and and will be relatively safe
et erunt quidem tutam ac winners
from this and may be in a position to
et in hoc statu
benefit from it are gonna be the people
Qui prodest Deo quia non agnus dei esse populus
that can work with the technology in a
qui cum technology operari per
way that really adds value and that
adiungit ut vere valorem et
would be people who are very creative
qui sit ipsa creatrix
that generate new ideas it will be
generate ideas quod erit novum
people that have interpersonal skills
qui sunt populus interpersonalem artes
and networks and can build sophisticated
et retiacula aedificare et non sophisticated
relationships with other people you know
relationes cum aliis scitis
and and and and things like that and of
ac ac ac talia
course it will also be people that own
Scilicet quod etiam sit hominibus, qui habent
lots of capital right because
caput rectum sortem
essentially what's happening here the
Quod suus 'hic autem per se fieri
big picture is that capital which
ut quod capitis est magnus picture
includes technology and machines and
et includit technology et machinis
algorithms is becoming more capable and
et fit capacior algorithms
displacing labor right so to people to
ut labore justum divellens
own capital which is a relatively few
qui est caput suum hi pauci respective;
people right because you know capital
qui nosti quod rectum caput
ownership is very concentrated right
angustior est ius proprietatis
those people are gonna do better and
qui sunt meliora et laudibus?
better right because they own the
ius quod habent melius
machines basically they own the robot as
ut fatentur plerumque robot machinas
you might say whereas the people that
Sed diceres quod
rely on their labor if they don't have
si labor non innititur
the specific skills to really work with
ut ad specifica solers vere opus
these technologies and and benefit from
illi beneficium Technologies
these technologies those people are
hi sunt qui vitae
going to be losers so that's the story
ut fama est iens victos
that we're gonna see in the future I
ut in futuro amet videre mihi
think and it basically is saying that
et factum puto, quod plerumque est dicens
things are gonna become even more
quae quidem tanto sunt facti gonna
unequal than they are now
quam nunc inaequalis
right now it's interesting that you talk
nunc suus 'interesting ut loqui
about the people who have the capital
de populo autem qui capitalia
are really kind of the ones that are
quae vere sunt quidam de ones
gonna benefit because it you know there
'agnus dei esse bonum quia non scitis
have been some who have that capital
fuerunt aliqui, qui ut capitis
that have spoken against it and I mean
quæ locutus sum contra eam, et sit
you have to worry about the fears that
Vos have ut fatigo circa timores
have been raised by people like Elon
concitantur in populo sicut cui successit Ahialon
Musk Stephen Hawking and others that
Stephanus arcu et alii, qui Cervus Red
someday I could pose a genuine
Ego aliquando posset pose a genuina
existential threat to humanity right so
periculum esse ne Dei homini recta
that's the second category of danger
Secundum genus est, quod de periculo
that I was talking about right there's
de me enim est iustum
something that's still right now is
tamen est aliquid quod nunc est,
really science fiction and the concern
et de scientia ficta realiter
there is that someday first of all we'll
nos omnes aliquando est primum
build a machine that has two human level
quod duorum hominum gradu aedificare machina
intelligence right again as I said
Iterum dixi quod intelligentia recta
before you know based on on the people I
prius scito fundatur super populum interfectionis meae
talked to could be 10 years away or it
loquebatur ad eam potest esse X annos vel auferetur
could be 200 years away right so
CC annos esse iustum ut auferat
and probably is is something like 80
et verisimile est esse aliquid simile LXXX
years at least away so you know it's
certe novi anni auferetur sic suus '
pretty far in the future but if we reach
Sin ad bella futura longe
that point most people believe that of
credo iam ut plurimum populi ab eo
course things are not going to stop at
quae utique non subsistere
that point the machine is gonna get even
eo loco est 'agnus dei adepto vel machina
smarter that is the natural expectation
scilicet naturalis opinionem nitidioribus
in part it might happen because the
partim quia contingere
Machine then decides to use its its
Ut machina sua censeat eius
superior internet intellect you to make
penitus superior intellectu est, ut
even smarter versions of itself so
et sic se versions of smarter
pretty soon you have what's called super
suus 'pulchellus cito in id quod vocatur Super
intelligence you have something that is
ingenii habes aliquid quod non
maybe much smarter than any human being
multo smarter quam omni homini maybe
something dramatically smarter some
quod dramatically aliquam smarter
people think it could be a thousand
putant esse mille
times smarter than we are or something
aut aliquid est smarter temporibus sumus
like that so we might be like you know a
ut sciant quod sicut similis
mouse or an insect relative to the
mus vel insecti, quae ad quaestionem
intellect of this machine right so at
Apparatus ad rectum intellectum huius
that point the question then becomes how
tunc fit illud, quod quaestio quam
do we control it how do we make sure
Non enim control et quomodo nos fac
that it still works with our best
non tamen operatur optimum
interests in mind right this is what's
ius hoc animi hominum studia inter se quis '
called the control problem and there are
et quaestio de potestate dicta sunt
serious people really really worried
populo gravi vere vere anxius
about this working on this the most
Hoc maxime opus hoc
famous of the people working on it is a
celebre est opus in populi
guy named Nick Bostrom who I actually
quo etiam nomine Guido, qui Nick Bostrom
also interviewed in the book and he
et interviewed in libro, et
wrote a pretty famous book that was a
satis celebre fuit, qui librum scripsit,
best-seller called super intelligence
Super vocatur intelligentia, maxime venditor
and so I talked to him in the book and
Et sic loquebatur ei in libro et
he's concerned about this he thinks it's
non est tibi curæ quod cogitat suus '
a real genuine issue that it potentially
vera genuina, quae est in potentia ad exitus
could be an existential threat obviously
quod esse non posset manifesto comminatione
that's very expectancy my own view on
id ipsum visum est expectatio mea
this is that it's good that some smart
hoc est, quod bonum est, ut aliquam dolor
people like Nick Bostrom and a few other
Nick Bostrom populus cum paucis
think tanks Elon must set up a
cogitare oportet constituere lacus Helon
think-tank called open AI which is
Al-cogitare cisternina, quae vocatur apertum est
working on this problem and I think
et puto opus in hac quaestio
that's great there's some really really
magnus illic 'aliquid quod suus' vere realiter
smart people that are doing good work on
ipsum opus bonum quod facis
this hmm and I think that's kind of an
hmm hoc esse puto quod genus
appropriate allocation of resources to
destinatio propriis opibus
this problem okay because it is very
hanc quaestionem bene, quod valde
speculative it does clearly lie far in
quod scilicet non tantum mentiri in speculativis,
the future I don't think we should have
Non enim oportet cogita in posterum
this massive concern over this I don't
de hoc magnum super hoc non faciunt
think we should have the government
ut non simus cogitare imperium
focused on this spending big you know
impendio magno focused in quo tu nosti
government funds or public funds on this
imperium aut pecunia in hac pecunia publica
I don't think we want Donald Trump
Non puto nos volo Donald BUCINUM
tweeting about this right I think it's
tweeting de hoc fas puto suus '
good where it is with a few smart people
ubi paucis bonis hominibus dolor
working on it
opus in eo
and I think that when you get rhetoric
Et puto, cum vos adepto ut oratio
like you've seen from Elon Musk where
Elon MOSCHUS vidi similis tui, a quo
he's talking about you know summoning
hes 'meditentur accersebant noveris
the demon and it's a bigger threat than
et daemonium ab ea, quam a maior comminatio
nuclear weapons or North Korea and all
nuclear arma et North Korea et
this stuff there's a risk that we become
illic 'a periculo fiet, ut hac supellectilem
too engrossed in that and we distract
nimis fidebat eo distrahere et
attention from the things that we really
operam in res quae realiter
need to be concerned about in the
in oporteat nos esse sollicitos
immediate future and this is the issue
et statim futurum est exitus
you raised earlier security also the
erexit et in securitatem ante vos
potential impact on privacy the
secretum est potentiale labefactum
potential for bias these are real issues
potentiale ad studium verae sint hae quaestiones
that are already concerned and also as
Iam hoc etiam quod attinet,
I've been talking about the potential
Ego cum iam de potentiale
impact on the job market and and on
et in foro, et fortius in officium
inequality these are things that are
quae haec inaequalitas
coming at us within the next few years
apud nos tunc veniens intra paucos annos
certainly within the next 10 20 years
certe in altera X annis XX
probably a lot sooner than that so
probabiliter multum, qui tam citius quam
that's where most of our media attention
ubi maxime operam ut 'media nostri
should be these other fears about an
si de istis timoribus
existential threat are legitimate I
periculum esse legitima mea
wouldn't dismiss them and say it's
Dicunt suus 'non dimittet eos
stupid or silly you shouldn't worry
stultus stulta aut quid solliciti estis
about it but I think it's okay that a
Puto autem quod suus 'okay sum de eo quod est
few smart people are worried about this
dolor hic sunt pauca sollicitus
I'm working on it for right now all
Im 'opus in eo, quia iam tota
right and so it sounds to me through the
Itaque mihi videtur rectum per
course of this conversation and Martin
Scilicet hoc colloquio et Martin
please correct me if I'm wrong but the
placere corrigere me si autem Fallo
people who are responsible for
qui reus est
developing the artificial intelligence
in developing artificialis intelligentia,
are aware of these potential problems
conscientiam autem horum potential problems
and and they're admittedly there are
et tu, et quidem sunt
some potential issues with AI that are
potentiale quaedam exitibus cum AI, qui
frightening and and they know about
et de horrendis et scitis
those and they implement those into the
illa et illas ad effectum deducendi
development process does that yes is
progressionem processus est etiam facit illa
that fair to say that's fair to say and
qui dicunt quod suus 'pulchra et aequum est et dicere
again speaking in terms of the two
iterum loqui quantum ad duo
general categories I laid out right
generum posui rectarum
everyone that I talked to in the book is
omnis qui loquebatur in me hoc est in libro
aware of the immediate concerns that
hoc est curam conscientiam immediatam
things like privacy and security and and
sicut et in securitatem et secretum rebus ac
bias and so forth and they are actively
salutem et studia active
working on these things they have
opus habent illa
different views about the further out
porro de diversis views ex
more futuristic existential threat some
Pellentesque existentiae quaedam comminatio more
of them are quite dismissive of that
quae sint ea dismissive
they really think that's not something
re vera autem quae videtur, non est aliquid,
we should worry about others do take
ut solliciti esse debemus accipere quod de aliis
that concern seriously good but I think
quae gravissime spectat bonum, sed puto
everyone agrees that it's okay if a few
cuique quod pauci bene
smart people work on it all right very
ipsum dolor recte faciunt eam
good so yes I mean I you know we can
Etiam ut bene sit tibi et tu scis possumus
have a reasonable level of a cup of
habere rationabile gradu calicem Domini
confidence there the people working on
fiducia est opus in populo
these technology
haec technology
is care about it right that they
aequum est curare ut
certainly know about these dangers and
certe novi et de his periculis
you know one danger we haven't talked so
ut cognoscatis, qui periculum non loquebatur
much about is weaponization the idea
ratio est fere weaponization
that that artificial intelligence could
quod potuit intellegentiae artificialis
be used in in autonomous weapons right
in ius esse in armis sui iuris,
that's not the same as the thing Elon
Non enim idem est Helon
Musk is worried about that means you
Cervus Red est sollicitus est quae te
know drones that might autonomously kill
ignavom fucos pecus ut sciatis quia libere interficere
somebody yeah that's something that we
yeah, nos quod quis ut '
have to worry about in relatively near
have ut fatigo in propius
future and and there are many people in
et ibi futura sunt, et hominibus
the artificial intelligence community
in artificialis intelligentia civitatem
did are very very concerned about this
non sunt de hoc
for example there are over a thousand
Sunt enim mille
researchers that have signed a petition
inquisitores, qui sunt signati petitionem
you know calling for a ban on these
nescitis Petitoque ban in illis
kinds of technologies because it could
quia non vitae generibus
be you know very dangerous and
tu nosti periculosa
disruptive interesting now we've kind of
Diximus autem quidam interesting turbulentos
gone from the beginning of what is it
quid de principio
and how does it relate yeah learning
memini enim se et doctrina
we've gone to the we got into the dark
si exieris ad nos got in tenebris
side of AI can we just bring it back a
Sicut enim nos reduc plagam urbis Ahi
little bit yes okay so you for one final
quod sic tam exigua bene quis vos finalem
question between all of your interviews
cuncta colloquiis inter quaestione tua
all of the research you've done you've
omnes investigationes ad te feci tibi Ive '
done what are you personally most
quid potissimum agendum personaliter
excited about when it comes to the
quantum ad concitatae
evolution of AI I'm excited about the
Ego sum excitatur de evolutione intellegentiae artificialis
potential that the technology has to
technology quod habet potentiale
transform the world for the better I
mundo melius non est de transform
mean the one of the best interviews in
in colloquiis sit unum de optimis
my book that I recommend everyone read
ut quisque legere librum meum, tibi commendo
is with demis hassabis who is the CEO of
CEO de demis qui cum hassabis
deepmind right this is maybe the most
fortasse magis hoc iure deepmind
famous AI company in the world is the
celebre in mundo sit societas intellegentiae artificialis
company that built the alphago system
cum ratio condidit alphago
that a lot of people heard about it
ut audivit de eo multus of populus
wanted the game of Go you can you can
Ite et vos voluit ludum vos can
there's actually a documentary called
illic 'vere dicta documentali
alphago on Netflix you can watch about
alphago netflix potes in circuitu
this's I'd highly recommend it what
id est quidquid ego tractet
Dennis says he's very famous for this
Et hoc ipsum dicit Dennis clarissimi
quote is that he wants to solve the
quote est, quod non vult solvere
problem of artificial intelligence and
forsit est artificialis intelligentia et
then he wants to use that to solve
et qui utuntur hoc vult solvere
everything else and that's really
et ut 'omne aliud realiter
interesting so what we're talking about
interesting est quod tu de
here right so AI is going to become the
hinc recta AI, ita est iens facti sunt
most important tool in our toolbox it's
Instrumentorum index magni momenti est instrumentum maxime in nostris
going to result in incredible
Ad consequuntur per fidem
breakthroughs in medicine and science it
Medicinae scientia in eam, et breakthroughs
can be used to address problems like
potest sicut solebat problematis occurratur
climate change it can be used to solve
clima mutatio possit solvere solebat,
the problem of new clean energy sources
novum industria mundum quaestionem de fontibus
right I mean maybe even you know global
Ego maybe etiam recte intelliguntur global scitis
poverty these are huge problems that
paupertas has difficultates, quae sunt ingens
humanity faces AI is going to be the
humanity respicit ad AI est iens futurus est
most important tool we have
maxime momenti instrumentum habemus,
to solve these problems because if you
quod si solvere quaestiones
think about it everything that we have
omne quod habemus cogitare de illa
in our world today everything that makes
quae in nostro mundo, quae facit hodie,
your life better than someone that lived
melior quam aliquis in vita tua qui habitabant
a hundred years ago or a thousand years
abhinc annos centum mille
ago is because of human ingenuity right
De humani ingenii est, quia rectum ante
right and I think I think we've lost
Et puto recte puto hoc potuit idcirco perierunt
Martin there just for a moment Martin
Martin est iustus pro momento Martin
I'm gonna let I'm gonna let that
Im 'agnus dei agnus dei fiat, quod fiat sum
reconnect for your final thought can you
postremum argumentum reconnect propter vos
finish it oh sorry we we lost you there
O si me paenitet et si ibi amisit consummare
Martin Martin can we just back up just
Martinus possumus iustus tergum sursum iustus
about ten seconds please okay so
Bene itaque placere decem secundis
artificial intelligence is going to be
artificialis intelligentia est iens futurus
the most important tool in our toolbox
maxime magna tool in Instrumentorum index
it is going to enable us to create
ut enable nos ad creare
things in the future that today we can't
quæ in futuro, quod hodie non possum
even imagine you know and and that's the
et tu scis quod ne imagine est
real promise of this technology that's
verum promissionem hoc technology ut '
what gets me excited and that's the
quid me recipit et provocatum est
reason that I talk about the challenges
quod non loquantur de challenges
and the downsides of this technology in
et Incommoda huius technology in
a particular way I talk about the
certo modo loqui de me
potential for inequality and
potentiale ad inaequalitatem et
unemployment and so forth because if we
quia si salutem otium
don't talk honestly about those problems
ut non loquantur de fide illorum problems
and and try to create solutions to those
et facere conantur illarum solutiones
problems and try to create a way for
et tentant creare problems in via
this to evolve in a way that's inclusive
hoc est ut evolve in inclusive
right that the benefits everyone and
et ad omnes qui jus beneficia
it's gonna be a backlash right people
suus 'agnus dei esse jus populus backlash
are gonna object they're gonna you know
quae scis amet objecto amet
people that are losing their livelihoods
Populus amittere victum sunt
sure falling behind they're gonna be
certe non es agnus dei esse a tergo cadit
against this technology and that's a bad
et malum quod contra elit
thing because it's an incredible benefit
aliquid quod suus 'incredibiliter bonum
for Humanity we don't want that we want
for Humanity autem non vis, ut vis
to find a way to adapt to this so that
ut inveniam viam ad hoc, ut ad aptet
we can leverage this technology on
possumus hoc technology in leverage
behalf of everyone and that's really my
et quod suus 'vere meis pro omnibus
primary message and really everything is
et quae sit vere prima nuntium
I do and in terms of all the writing
Verba facio, et omnes scripto
that I've done in this area we've been
Feci quod habuimus hac
speaking with New York Times bestselling
loqui cum New York Times bestselling
author Martin Ford and he is the author
Martin Ford auctor et auctor est,
of Architects of intelligence brand new
ex intelligentia novam Architectus
just came out and it's available
et factum est sicut suus 'available
everywhere right now you can also
vos can quoque nunc ubique
support us if you'd like use the links
si velis uti posse de nobis putabis links
that we've posted below and that will
postquam ei reí missae inferius, et voluntatem
allow you to purchase through Amazon as
ex empto sinet Amazon
well Martin it has been a pleasure
Martin optime Felix fuit
having you on the show thank you so much
tibi gratias ago tibi tantam habens in spectaculum
for being here thank you
gratias ago tibi, quia non hic,
[Music]
[Musica]
you
vos